now now you have me thinking maybe we
need to write some hacker fantasy books
where it's you're just like late at
night just sitting by the fire you're
just reading it through you're just
fantasizing about awesome bugs and
they're all hypothetical scenarios that
just get that just make you really like
full mode
post message knocked on the door who
could
[Music]
yo yo
yo what's up my dude how's it going
pretty good man we have a ton of news
articles to talk about this week that I
am Mega hype about
yeah this is I don't I don't know like
it feels like all of a sudden in the
last few weeks there's been a ton of
really interesting articles about this
type of stuff so it feels like a really
good opportunity to make an episode
about it it just Ebbs and flows man like
I feel like for a couple weeks there
were no write-ups that were interesting
at all around and then like I want to
say it was a Saturday too I open up my
Twitter and I'm like whoa whoa whoa so
the uh the bookmark list for the Pod got
really long that day
yeah I know exactly what you mean we'll
we'll talk about maybe some of the
reasons why because I I have some ideas
as to as to why that might be happening
but uh yeah but yeah this is a it's a
really good week we got a ton of really
cool stuff to talk about sweet so
um you know what let me go ahead and
start off with the first one since I've
got a few more than you
um okay so this one uh
was brought to my attention by none
other than shubs infosec Au shabam
himself The Legend killer hacker yeah um
definitely go follow him on Twitter uh
if you're not already
um this was a write-up by a company
called el Tam
um I I always try to pronounce these
things on stream and you know saying
these things
but I think I think this was a really
good example uh and we'll link it down
it's called pone assistant uh
controlling homes via a home assistant
rce
um I think this is a really good example
of uh one some of the stuff we're about
to talk about today which is uh source
code analysis
um and also just sort of attack a vector
mentality and like the way that they
approach this code base is really good
and the write-up here has a lot of
really good information about how they
approach the code base so
um we'll talk about this a little bit
more as we get into the topic but
um you'll see that they follow the same
flow that I I talked about even back in
my um my talk that I did on the grafana
srf years ago
um which is essentially you know when
you're approaching a code base you know
you want to decide whether you're open
to finding unauthenticated but or
authenticated bugs or unauthenticated
bugs
um and you know and you got to make a
decision based off of that because if
you're only going to be looking at
unauthenticated bugs
um then you know you really need to get
laser focused on where the
authentication is and you know figure
out a way around that or or figure out
work within the parameters of the things
that are intentionally scoped to be
unauthenticated which is what the
attackers do in this specific post
they're able to get rce by essentially
pivoting a reverse proxy
um and path traversing back up and
hitting
um endpoints that are supposed to be a
past authentication but through a a uh
an endpoint that has authentication set
to false so another class example of
path traversal destroying a Target here
it's really funny that this bug because
this bug is in home assistant I don't
know if you realize but this is but this
is like that home automation software
that I use oh no way is it really is
that yeah yeah so when I saw this I was
like oh oh yeah luckily it looks like
they published it's like
um a couple of months like after you
know it was fixed yeah
okay and mine is already like behind
zero two which is another thing that we
talked about so it's not even exposed to
the public internet but super super
interesting vulnerability it makes me
wonder like what else is in there
because I honestly haven't I've never
looked at like you know the code base of
it myself
um but I can imagine that there's a lot
of room for error yeah for sure those
types of systems and it was saying um I
was reading through this let's see if I
can find it's under the section called
Fine finding interesting Integrations it
says there are around 150 internal
quality Integrations including the HTTP
integration
um and so those are a bunch of
Integrations that could be leading to
attack vectors there and I think they
also say a lot of those were HTTP later
down and enabled by default
um later down in the article so
definitely something to keep your eye on
I did that's funny though I I love that
I uh that I picked this one for the Pod
and that's actually on your own setup do
you I mean does it it's got Auto
patching on or do you manually patch it
or what it's it sends me a notification
but it's like you just click a button to
update and it does all of it on its own
so it's it's like pretty much automatic
I'm sure you could probably set it to
automatically update the main risk being
that like it might break some of your
stuff if it does so that's just like one
thing to to keep in mind but I think
systems like this where there's a lot of
like trust
um sort of like built into it where like
you're just kind of assuming like that
you're already like in a privileged
standpoint if you're doing good stuff on
here then it's it's kind of like a
difficult scenario to to like analyze
whether or not this is something you
should be worried about or not but um
it's easy enough for this you just
update the version
definitely adds another layer of of
importance to having good Network
segmentation and you're even in your
home setup so when your guests are
coming over
or you know you're giving your
contractor access to your you know
giving anybody access because at the end
of the day their device could be pwned
as well so right um giving them access
to your home network you're going to
want to put that on a guest on a guest
division of that yeah or something yeah
a separate VLAN for sure
so all right cool um definitely check
out that one we'll link it in the uh in
the description of the episode
um or you could just go get it from
shubs's Twitter uh that's where I got it
so yeah yeah so the next one that I that
I want to talk about
um and these are all along you know the
theme of basically source code analysis
because that's today's topic
um this is a Blog I think we may have
talked about it last week or the week
before or something it was uh from Andre
zurich's ACB
um and his company called ethi hack
um they are you know an automated
security company that he uh he started
um they're doing a lot of really cool
cool research
um and this most recent post that they
made it's talking about this get uh
basically a configuration injection it
was a bug within how git is doing its
configuration parsing I love a good I
love a good configuration injection man
yeah I'll leave it to Andre of all the
people to find a bug in git car you know
what I mean oh my gosh
so yeah this is a really cool bug it's
very very similar to something that we
were working on
for this last life hacking can you
imagine look at that yeah
wow damn yeah super crazy uh so
basically the the gist of this is that
the get when it's parsing through like a
git config file
um it will parse the different sections
according to you know different
characters so it'll check does it start
with like an Open Bracket that would
signify that it's a section that type of
stuff
um but what Andre realized is that as
it's reading through this it reads 10 24
bytes at a time
um and basically like it there's not a
buffer overflow there because it's like
checking how much it's reading however
the way that it's parsing it leads to
other vulnerabilities
so essentially you can
create a line that's over 10 24
characters when it reads the 1024 it
gets halfway through that line very
similar to the bike that
was just exploited yeah and then it
starts again like halfway through that
line after 10 24 characters and reads
the rest of it which then lets you
basically create like a a bogus section
within there that adds it in
um and so through sections you can have
it run different commands and all that
kind of stuff so you basically overwrite
like the core section and have it run a
command when you do like a git sub
module update or something so
um it's a really really cool bug
um it's very straightforward simple blog
post I'd highly recommend going and
reading it and checking it out and uh it
it's again it's one of those situations
where I feel like uh I should I should
be looking at this yeah you know like
why haven't I been looking at this I
love how Andre makes it so simple too
like you literally just like this this
blog post is not even a page long of
text yeah yeah you get like the maximum
amount of fomo for not having found this
video this man could fit this in like a
Twitter thread for sure
um and so yeah that's that's amazing and
and I think we do see this is a really
interesting trick this whole concept of
like overflowing not not necessarily
overflowing but
um dicing up the lines in a
configuration file
um we just did this with a separate
service
um and git was also vulnerable to it so
that's at least two in the past couple
weeks that have been vulnerable to this
sort of things so anytime you're you're
looking at configuration file injection
or anything with the configuration file
that's being sucked up into a different
context this could definitely be a cool
trick to uh keeping your hat
um yeah dude I love stuff like this this
is the stuff that gets my blood pumping
because it's like yeah I've got now from
now on for the rest of my life whenever
I come to these sort of situations I'm
gonna have that trick in my pocket and I
know it's gonna work again which is
clutch yeah the config file parsing
stuff I feel like we're we're very like
gradually getting out of the phase of
like buffer overflows like use after
free that stuff still exists like don't
get me wrong but I think it's now
transitioning a little bit more into
those things are so commonplace that
they're not happening as frequently
anymore and instead you're getting to
these other types of bugs which are like
they're parsing it safely but they're
parsing it wrong right so like there's
no buffer overflow but they're not
expecting like they were too focused on
one thing to like recognize the others
so and it doesn't always result in rce
you know in the scenarios that Joel and
I have been working on lately with
configuration file injection which was
uh a running theme in the bugs that
we've found at a at a certain life
hacking event that happened lately
um there you know they're you're limited
to the application context like you said
because it's not like a super duper low
level vulnerability where you're like
okay let me just you know override this
pointer and jump to my code right it's
it's more of a like okay now I am able
to inject into this context that I
should be able to inject to how can I
use this application to to break the uh
you know authorization scheme and in
effect you know things outside the
current scope so yeah yeah I think I
think that's definitely something to to
keep an eye out for
yeah I mean it it's almost like
the majority of the bug becomes like
figuring out how to work within this
like absolutely weird environment right
be so like for our case like we we had
to figure out like oh you can you know
enter this directive in the config file
multiple times and then the second one
will overwrite the first one and it
looks like Andre had a very similar type
of Discovery here which is that like if
you put the core section in your git
config twice as a result of the exploit
the second one overwrites the first one
and it does the second one's action so I
think a lot of the challenge around this
yeah you can you can probably find this
pretty easily but then the challenge is
how do I use whatever's available within
the config file whether it's available
within this service or whatever that I'm
that I'm hacking to get rce or get an
alify or whatever like yeah a a classic
a classic case of this that I'll just do
a little self-promotion here now I'll do
a little Sam promotion this is a Sam
herb I come in there for a couple
minutes but this is largely Sam or just
doing the thing he rocks at which is
looking at code and finding bones um we
did a talk at Defcon last year called
crossing the chasm
kasm and that's another really fun story
of a configuration file injection that
resulted in rce but not directly because
you cannot get rce very easily from
nginx configuration file injection which
we learned very well those which is
surprising because you would expect that
like of all the things that could
probably like run a script automatically
or something like engine X like yeah
yeah I mean and there are some
situations where you can but our
specific context which I think I could
see it being in context where
um you know configuration injection
happens pretty regularly we couldn't so
definitely check that out check that out
for Sam herb and uh uh yeah
um we'll link that down below yeah for
sure all right let's see what do we got
next
um you want to talk about uh Drew Bob's
yeah okay dude let me just say G Bob's
the man we we have we've talked about
them before but they're they're yeah
hacker always killing it always creating
awesome bugs and this is just another
example rocking it um so literally go
turn on tweet notification I have tweet
notifications on for very few people
this guy's one of them um so definitely
definitely check uh them out on Twitter
and also check out this link that we'll
put in the description called a smorgish
board of a bug chain and man is that an
accurate title because he puts together
a post message bug a misconfigured Json
P endpoint laugh bypass domx's s cores
and sea surf to pone an application and
this is the stuff that just makes me so
happy dude like this this shows this is
the stuff that I'm trying to talk to my
mentees about where it's like
it's not the stuff that you're gonna
find in the textbook in the tutorial or
on the YouTube video this is what
happens when you have a more
comprehensive understanding of these uh
these the ways that websites interact
together and this is something oh man
here we go off go ahead listen I was
gonna hold myself back here too but now
you're getting me fired so dude it's
it's thing man like a lot of the
education out there for five pound and
and it has made very large leaps and
strides over the past couple years right
um since we started bookbound even you
know it's great but I will say a lot of
it is focused on how to get the Bounty a
very specific
um you know how to find this specific
vulnerability in this specific context
and I think there's less talk about wow
this is a restriction that's normally
present in the browser if this
restriction breaks down in some sort of
way if it degrades or if there's a a
hole in it here and there here's what
that means you know and here's what that
means for the situation and I think this
write-up we can't go through all the
details because it's super long write up
in it because it's a mega complex bug
but you'll see how his attack flow
changes he says okay you know I want to
find a sea serve okay well how can I get
the csif token well there's a permissive
course situation and okay so maybe I can
use that and then he finds like uh looks
at the out of scope areas to find
something that could interact with the
main asset over through cores and then
he finds a post message bug and then he
bypasses some stuff and then he finds a
Json P endpoint and breaks the you know
and it's just it's just an amazing tale
that I mean like if there was a you know
almost like a novel version if there was
if there was hacking fantasy for me this
is what it would be like I just I don't
know man I love it so shout out now I'm
thinking maybe we need to write some
hacker fantasy books where it's you're
just like late at night just sitting by
the fire and just reading through you're
just fantasizing about awesome bugs and
they're all hypothetical scenarios
they just make you really like faux mode
post message knocked on the door who
could it be
no it was an unauthenticated bypass
no oh man I love it yeah
um so anyway if that wasn't enough for
you to just go read the freaking
write-up
um something's wrong with you so uh
definitely go check that out and then
also I will shout out this as well
because he tweeted afterwards um let me
pull it up actually right here he
tweeted afterwards he's like man
everyone really loved that article I'm
so glad but also you should check out
this other article that I wrote
um so let me pull it up right here
Fearless cores
um
which is uh another article written by
him
um and so definitely go check that out
and and give some of his other work some
love too
um even if it's not a direct vulum
write-up
yeah yeah super awesome let's see what
we got next here
um cool uh yeah no there's um there's a
couple posts there's this uh this one
from ankur sundara about cookie bugs oh
okay yeah dude I freaking love this one
you want to take this photo should I
take this one go ahead go ahead okay all
right cool yeah and then there's this
other other one uh or another one after
the Carlton okay yeah that one's a
really good one too um but I'll I'll
talk about this one first so
man see this is um okay so this is
another awesome awesome piece of of
writing of research done uh by this guy
ankur sundara I I don't know this
researcher but I have a very high amount
of respect for them now because of this
this post and this post is a great
example of like the stuff that makes me
really excited from research perspective
it's not necessarily like here is this
great new cve that I've already released
and patched and you know look at this
cool bug that I found no this is
literally one of his sections is some
interesting browser Behavior yeah and I
just this is like the evolution of like
an exercise cheat sheet you know what I
mean yeah and it just it makes my my
pulse just go through the roof man
because it's like you know this is the
weird that you need to know about
to to be to find crazy bugs you got an
and I didn't even know about a lot of
this stuff so
some of the cool things I'll I'll shout
out in here is they do some research on
subdomains and super domains they do
some research on underscore underscore
host and underscore underscore secure
prefixed cookies which I've seen around
and have just been too lazy to look into
those actually have a meeting and uh
have some some implementation in the
browser which means the name of a cookie
that you that you set can determine some
of its attributes right which is like
yeah
what that's that's crazy
yeah and and it's also like where does
this fall apart in terms of like Chrome
versus Firefox versus Safari like all
that kind of like is this browser
specific like where's the is it
standardized if so like where right like
reading through the rfcs and that kind
of stuff so I think it's really awesome
that like
um what there was another example I was
thinking about
um
there was a blog post we talked about
early on in in the podcast that was
basically going through like all the
different ways to get I think it was to
like get iframes or something in a page
oh yeah yeah let me see if I can find
that yeah very similar type of like
research where this is basically it's
not so much like it's like what you talk
about it's not like
it's not news security research per se
it's not like a CBE or anything yeah
it's just documenting somewhere
like how this stuff works that could
probably be used later for some like
really epic bugs yeah I just I love this
type of research and you're absolutely
right like that is and I I found the
article as well I'm gonna put that
article in our in our description as
well this time because you're absolutely
right like what a
yeah I Can't Tell You Why can't I click
on this it's crazy I think a lot of
hunters get really like
um uneasy about publishing this kind of
stuff because it's almost like you're
talking about the secret sauce and like
the secret types of like knowledge based
stuff that you have but I think it's
really important to publish this kind of
information because so many times as a
researcher I've been
exporting a bug and I'm trying to find
this type of information about what I'm
hacking on I'm trying to find the weird
behaviors I'm trying to find like oh
where like what we just talked about
what's like a weird config entry that
does something unexpected how can I run
a shell script through through a config
file right like those types of like
weird behaviors or weird things to know
about often you have to find them in
like much more convoluted ways where
yeah you have to search almost like as a
developer like how do I do this thing
and it primes the brain too you know
like like when you release research like
this even though it's not like
groundbreaking rce you know it lets me
realize hey ah I I can influence you
know a flag on a cookie using the name
and I can influence like the browser via
cookie ordering like this is another
thing they talk about they do research
on cookie ordering here and what happens
if you send it if you set an empty
cookie like this is so cool there's no
name for this cookie and the browser
thinks it's just one cookie but when it
gets sent you can smell ugly and other
cookies and it's like what and so yeah
yeah it's this sort of thing is just so
valuable so big shout out to this guy
um definitely read through the whole
thing there's a way of breaking
document.cooking in Chrome which is just
super cool there's cookie smuggling
cookie injection like
such so much good stuff here
yeah yeah and he talks about like the
rfcs and like ties it all back to like
the original types of like documentation
like how this stuff is supposed to be
parsed and like I think he even
mentioned that there's like up up like
basically a hard-coded bug within the
RFC
um that like the jetty maintainer
maintainer is like talked about like
publicly so there's just a ton of really
interesting information and knowledge to
be had from this article so go give it a
read
um give it a bookmark and yeah you know
I'm sure you're gonna end up using these
things later solid okay I've got two
follow-up little things on that and then
you can talk about Carlson's thing
um so there's a comment under this
Twitter uh under this tweet that says uh
nice post I have also found maybe a zero
day in PHP which will allow you to
bypass this
um because of the use of underscores so
remember there's that weird thing in PHP
where like if you send a dot it gets
converted to an underscore and or like
vice versa and so that's another piece
is like anytime you see these these
underscores and dots you can know that
hey in PHP there's some Quirk there I
love quirks technical quirks just get me
hype and then the other awesome comment
that came from that was a post by James
Kettle which somehow had flown under my
radar
um I don't I normally religiously read
everything that James Kettle puts out
but this web cash entanglement uh novel
Pathways to poisoning
um research that he published has a lot
of the same sort of things of like
here's some weird Edge case stuff where
you can do with like you know perimeter
smuggling and and a bunch of caching
um sort of gadgets or or methodologies
that you can use to change stuff
together so definitely go give this one
another read
um there's some really cool tricks in
here that you can be aware of and use in
different tags as well yeah yeah I feel
like it's like the sweet spot where
um we experience this a little bit where
once you've been hacking on something
for like a really long period of time
um you may like come out of it from like
a week of straight hacking and not have
any findings but what you do have is
like a lot of learnings and those types
of things are the types of stuff that is
going into these blogs it's it's
learning it's like here's like weird
behavior that I noticed here's like
strange functionality that exists and
I'm not sure how to exploit but I
noticed and seems weird right and like
just putting that out there
is so so useful you see it in James
kettle's research as well you know he's
so familiar with like web cash poisoning
and cash deception and he's been doing
it for so long that he just has this
wealth of like weird things you know
like like weird behavior that he just
needs to write it down somewhere and
just like be like here I don't know what
to do with this but somebody look at it
it's crazy when you meet him in person
too I remember meeting him in person in
the last London event
um and just like seeing him sit there
and it just sort of he was sitting at
the table with me one time and kind of
talking through like oh what if this and
what if that and I was like man you just
know so much weird you know like
and so that was really cool and um yeah
and speaking of London
yeah next live hacking event is on the
calendar
um your boy Joel and I uh are gonna be
hitting up London for Life hacking event
with hack one hopefully James Kettle
will be there it'd be awesome to see him
again if not I'm actually I'm gonna pop
open his Twitter right now and send him
a message be like yo you should come to
this even if you're not you know if
you're not hacking just shop They're
Gonna Let You in give me give me a hug
um and yeah so definitely excited for
that okay what's the last one we got on
the news
cool yeah so this is just like uh this
was something that was tweeted out by um
Johann Carlson
um j-o-a-a-x car on Twitter nice and um
basically this is a new feature within
Chrome
um the
112. I yeah from man that's a lot of
versions uh but yeah in the latest I
think the latest the you know version
112 of Chrome or newer they added a new
feature to the dev tools where you may
have noticed uh for example if you
inspect element on something or you it's
like on a link in your Dev tools to like
a Javascript file it'll take you to this
tab called sources and sources will have
basically a file Tree on the left side
of all of the like files and scripts and
CSS and HTML and everything that's been
loaded by the page uh within this like
context right and so you can click
through that file tree you can you know
view the source code of a Javascript
file that's loaded or whatever you can
set breakpoints I think it's really
meant for developers to do like
debugging type of stuff but it's there
right
and one of the new features that they
added to make this easier for developing
I guess but it also makes this
simultaneously a lot nicer for hackers
is you can ignore files from that tree
so you can totally like exclude them
um from like the list so you can even
hide them if you want
um but you can also make it so that they
just like aren't they you know are
ignored and that they have a checkbox in
here that lets you automatically exclude
all third party scripts right so
depending on the type of hacking that
you're doing if you're really focused on
say a webpack like Source map or
something right you can ignore you can
just right click ignore all the third
party scripts clean it up now you know
exactly what you need to look at makes
your life a lot easier dude that's so
helpful like in devtools I have a love
hate relationship with devtools because
devtools is really
kind of crappy sometimes like it'll lag
out and it'll like bug and you have to
restart Chrome and it's like ah please
and yeah there's some bug that's going
on right now where like even if you
check
um deactivate breakpoints it still does
the break points which is drives me nuts
um but yeah I know it's great to see
them adding features like this and this
is definitely something I'll use because
the less friction you have the less like
no that's not it in your brain even if
it's just like quickly skipping over it
that is that is going to affect your
your flow because your brain's going to
be able to focus better on the script at
hand so great feature yeah
yeah and it looks like it also will
basically like if you set it break point
and you're looking through the call
frame like the whole call stack frame it
will allow you to remove that them the
ignored files from that from that stack
as well so it just you know cleans a lot
of stuff up makes your life easier
um you know and it's really awesome uh
really awesome sweet feature that's just
built in now alrighty man uh we are we
are 27 minutes in already 27 minutes
with the uh yeah with just the news so
we might have to keep this a little bit
more concise than we thought but
um we wanted to talk today with you all
about uh source code review techniques
um and what kind of stuff we're using to
do source code review
um how this is applicable in a bug
Bounty context uh the ins and outs of it
you know lead hacker techniques for that
sort of thing
um so that's what we're going to be
talking about today
um let's see where do you want to start
Joel
uh let's just start with like the basics
right so like source code
um it's the the easiest way that I found
to view source code is one of two
methods Visual Studio code which is a
glorified text editor and an IDE of some
kind
um the IDE is really useful if you need
more uh like fine-grained language level
information
um so I'm not even going to say like go
to definition like the right click like
go to definition and all that type of
stuff because you can get a lot of that
through like a visual studio code or
atom or sublime or whatever you want to
use through plugins but that is a lot of
what you'll get through an IDE
generally most of the time I'm going to
say I'm using visual studio code because
it's just easier to navigate and search
and it's fast and it's lightweight yeah
um one of the things that that I sort of
picked on so I'm just for context for
those of you maybe that are listening
for the first time
um I'm a full-time book Bounty Hunter
and Joel is a Silicon Valley Engineers
security dude right and so Joel's thing
is that he actually does this for a
living
yeah I do review source code basically
every single day yeah and so um the last
event that we did uh you know your voice
Scrappy uh full-time book Bounty Hunter
over here was like all right let's maybe
just open up all the source code in vim
and like rip grab through all the stuff
and Joel is like no no no no good sir
like let me introduce you to something
called vs code and and he had before and
I had I'd used vs code before but I will
say like watching you use vs code um in
this last event really changed my my
opinions on like
using vs code versus using something
like Vim plus rip graph or something
like that for for going through various
files um and and so yeah and I think one
of the main things like like you said
was like the S code has the capability
to do the stuff like Find definition and
actually parse all of the the you know
code that you're reading here and allow
you to jump around using sort of logical
um uh flows in like it understands the
code which is really cool and that was
not something that I had installed I'm
I'm uh I'm sad to admit so and that I I
got that you you got that for me by just
opening up
um the Via extension videos and then
going to extensions right yep yeah so a
lot of the time you'll notice that like
the extensions are what make vs code
good
um and so basically what you'll find is
that you might be working on some
specific type of protocol or a file or
something and it'll often recommend you
like hey do you want I see you're
working on a DOT Pi file do you want to
download the python extension and you
may ignore that but what the python
extension is going to do and typically
it'll explain this if you look at the
extension in the marketplace within vs
code it'll say like this ads
intellisense and it adds code completion
and it adds like all these things that
are really nice intellisense is
basically just you know like suggesting
functions that exist properties that
exist it's intelligently it understands
your code base so it knows like oh
you're you're working with this object
this object has these available
properties and it will suggest those in
a drop down
and that type of like information is
super super useful because basically
that means your your editor is working
alongside you to make your life easier
so if you're looking at a function and
you want to know where is that function
defined most of the time you could just
either right click and click go to
definition or you can do a command or
control click on the name of it and
it'll take you right to where it's
defined that just makes your life easier
instead of having to copy the name of
the function control F for it look
through all the options find the
definition click on it manually like go
back and forth instead it's like you
know one click yeah
um that's so that was huge yeah yeah the
extensions are are pretty huge
um I think without extensions vs code is
kind of you know it's fine it's very
usable I still would use it but I think
the extensions really make it much more
feature complete yeah um and it's it's
much more flexible I think even just
having you know the built-in propensity
for command line or um keyboard
shortcuts as well is really helpful just
Ctrl P like okay I know that this file
is going to be in this specific spot uh
or this specific name so control P type
the name of the file enter boom you know
I've got it up depending no matter where
it is in my directory structure excuse
me
I didn't have to bounce around the the
folder you know expanding things you
know collapsing things no just Ctrl P
type of the name boom and it's open and
yeah and it was also really helpful
um for me to see how uh you know we
could trace the flow of code
um through various functions
um and how to do that with you know
dividing the screen into different parts
so okay we're over here in this function
and then you know we call this line and
that jumps to a different file so I pop
it open on it on a you know split the
screen pop it open I hop right over
there and so you know having all of that
in front of you at one time makes the
the friction of jumping in and out at
like you have to do for these sort of
things a lot less present and and helps
you trace the code a lot better I think
yeah yeah I mean that's like one of the
amazing features about vs code is that
it's so modular in that sense where you
can just split your window vertically or
horizontally or into three sections or
you can you know focus on one of those
sections instead of all of them at the
same time there's like so many options
um that that control or command P thing
that you talked about
um is super huge there are like two main
versions of that there's command shift B
which they call it the command palette
and basically the command palette is
everything like every like action like
every command so to speak that you can
do within vs code this is why I wanted
to do this episode as well yeah is
because like while we were hacking on
stuff I didn't really want to like
interrupt the flow and be like Joel
teach me how to use vs code but that's
what we're doing here today is actually
my sneaky motive for this episode I was
nerds type the whole time control shift
p and now I'm okay I'm looking at all of
the different actions I can do okay cool
yeah yeah let me pull it up too so yeah
command shift B this is called your
command palette you'll notice that
there's like a right arrow at the
beginning if you remove that then that's
equivalent to doing control P or command
P which is basically your file switcher
so if you type an arrow in there then
that's all the available commands and
you'll see there's a huge list they're
usually categorized by like
um there's like the built-in functions
and then they'll be like an extension so
it'll be like extension Name colon
action right
um and so there's a lot of different
things that you could do for example you
can reset your Zoom from here you can
format whatever file you have open from
here you can open a terminal you can go
to the matching bracket like you know
there's like a ton of like different
options and things that you can do from
here and it's very very generic right so
this is like I I don't want to over
speak by saying it's everything that you
can do in vs code but it's very very
close to like basically all of the sort
of actions and stuff that you can
imagine that you can do within vs code
and in addition to that it shows you if
you have a keyboard uh like shortcut
already assigned to that yeah I love
that feature of it because then you know
and so you can press that Ctrl shift p
and you can start typing you can use
your words to describe the action you
want to do and then boom right on the
other hand the right hand side you see
okay that's the keyboard shortcut for
that next time I'm not even gonna have
to press command shift p I can just hit
that that shortcut or this is one of my
top
um used uh keyboard shortcut or things
for this command palette is preferences
open keyboard shortcuts so I can
reassign different shortcuts as well so
Ctrl shift p open keyboard shortcuts
that allows you to redefine your your
shortcuts which is really helpful for
you know gaining that Traction in the
application where you don't even have to
think about using it yeah and you'll
notice that like some of these for
example open keyboard shortcuts it'll
say control K control s
vs code supports um a very like this is
in vim and stuff it's called chords
where basically you have like multiple
step type of uh keyboard shortcuts so
like in
t-box for example you have like your
control character which is like control
b or control a for screen right so like
if you do control a then something else
like Ctrl a d to detach in in like a
screen session right right that's the
same as like Ctrl K control s it's it's
two separate like in a row so you do
control K it says okay I'm waiting for
the next thing then you do control s and
it goes okay that's what you want so you
can have more complex uh keyboard
shortcuts that aren't you don't have to
like combine Ctrl shift alt meta like
everything all together you can just do
like control K and then something else
and that Gates it and I love that too
because a lot of times I want to be able
to do stuff with one hand so I want it
to be predominantly my left hand so I
want to you want it to be you know
control a something can you know a even
the little tilde up at the top left hand
corner I use that all the time so I can
just do things primarily with my left
hands and even if my right hand is
coming back from the mouse going over to
the key we're getting a little technical
here but you know even if my right hand
is is coming from the mouse to the
keyboard I can still be using my left
hand to control the flow of the
application
um so I like that a lot okay man cool
cool stuff there in vs code
um here's the thing
I kind of put the sections in the wrong
order in the dock so we we just talked a
bunch about vs oh yeah and I do actually
have one more question so I'm not even
sure you know what to tell you what
screw the order I'm gonna ask the
question okay so here's what here's the
thing this is a question for you Joel
which you may uh answer on the spot or
this could be a question for the
audience afterwards um and see what what
you know everyone comes up with
um
I would like so after this last live
hacking event I I realized that
um even with vs code's amazing features
for jumping around and you know popping
open different tabs and all that great
stuff
I still get lost in very complex
functions so I keep on having to go back
to the source you know and then trace it
all the way down and try to reach the
sink but I kind of get lost
um in that flow what I would really like
to be able to do is to find something
that's sort of like a break point but
it's like a logical flow indicator so
you know we start in this function where
where we you know have the source and
then we go down eight lines and then I
have a little dot next to the line and
something like that and that has one on
it right and then that's goes into the
next function right and so I go to the
next function and I say okay you know
here's the important line and then I
press a button next to it and that has
two you know and then I want to be able
to jump back and forth and say like okay
go back to one go back to two go back to
three so that I can just kind of Trace
in my mind the flow of the code I don't
know if that's something like that
exists but if it does I need it
if it does I'm not aware of it I can
think of a couple of things that I've
done for like similar Behavior so like
very kind of related
oftentimes I use the forward and back
function within vs code very frequently
yeah so like I rebind those to either
like control like square bracket like
open and close square bracket for back
and forwards or like the mouse like the
buttons on my mouse the like forward and
back buttons on the side of my mouse
okay
um and I'll use that because that
basically takes you back to the last
place that your cursor was like was so
if I'm like clicking through stuff then
I can just click back and I can hop back
instead but that kind of jumping between
like Steps one and four for example like
that is very difficult a good way that
you can do that like in the meantime
there I I don't let me see if I can find
what it's called but uh there's a to-do
um yeah to do highlight it's called to
do highlight yeah so this is an
extension right like I talked about
extensions add a ton of like function
analy to vs code it's called to do
highlight it's got three and a half
million downloads a hundred uh 100
ratings at four and a half stars
um and basically what it does is exactly
what it says it does it highlights to do
comments so if you do like a comment
with to do colon whatever it will
highlight it and it creates a separate
section at the bottom like underneath
your file explorer on the left side of
vs code called like to Do's tree and
basically you can see all the different
to-do's that are within your open
project and then you can click to go
between them so you could you could mark
it the same way like you could do like
step one or something like that and you
could just mark it that way as like a
temporary kind of hack I guess
um yeah no that's and that might work
that that actually seems like it's the
closest thing I've seen to what I'm
looking for there because yeah yeah I
would love to have like you mentioned a
little tree that says okay step one step
two step three step four you know and
then because sometimes there's a lot
there's stuff you have to bypass along
the way you know you I think you know
the thing that I'm talking about where
we had that if statement that I was just
like oh no we're screwed and then you're
like no we can just we can just bypass
this whole block of Code by doing XYZ
and I'm like I love you Joel
um yeah and so you know some that that
that little block of code that we were
talking about there was way way deep
probably six functions deep in the call
stack
um and we had to go all the way back up
to one before we we got to the to the to
the sink
um and so having some sort of you know a
way to mind map all that out would be
really cool
um definitely going to use the the uh
let me copy this into the notes for the
for the show too the uh to do highlight
previous code until I see something
better for that
yeah I really like that I I mean
honestly that should be like a pretty
straightforward extension to create
um so I think that that might be
something we could look into because
that sounds quite useful it does okay so
we we kind of jumped the gun because we
got yeah we jumped the gun a little bit
about vs code
um but one of the things I want to talk
about first was so as a as a book Bounty
Hunter sorry I've got this little I
don't know if you heard it but I've got
this little like popper uh I can't even
hold up the number of fidget toys I have
sitting on my desk in front of me it's
really nice to have little fidget toys
around so if you hear popping in the
background it's me playing with this
thing
um but uh so let's talk about getting
the source code because as a bug Bounty
Hunter you're not an internal you know
uh you're not inside an organization so
a lot of times you don't have access to
source code so how do you get access to
source code well there's a couple ways
that I wanted to break down one of
course we always have access to
client-side source code so you always
have access to the JavaScript you always
have access to the HTML CSS
um I Heard somewhere that there's
client-side python that happens
sometimes yuck for one but for two
whatever you're gonna have access to
that so do that
um uh one of the very few times I will
say yuck to python but um
yeah so you've always got access to that
but there's also a couple other ways
that you can get access to source code
um the first one that I wanted to talk
about was demos slash free trials
um and this is something I think we
mentioned on a previous pod
um but there there's a lot of really
amazing hackers that will go through a
very long process to get access to
source code
um maybe I've heard of some people going
as far as signing up for it with their
for like a demo with their company with
this company going to the demo you know
talking to the sales person and being
like hey you know I really just need to
get my hands on the product I think can
you send me a memo and they're like sure
oh man and so and but at the end of the
day they get their hands on the code and
a lot of times it's a Docker container
sometimes it's actual like you know a
zip file that has the code that you need
to run in it but um doing anything like
that that can get you access to source
code can be absolutely huge because now
you're not testing blind you know what
you're doing and um and that's that's a
game changer yeah well and oftentimes
like yeah he's oh man here stopped that
before here's the Joel's catches jumped
on his piano already kind of
yeah
um yeah no so I I think for like me
this is like a personal thing yeah I
draw the ethical line kind of at the
sales call basically so like if I have
to get into a sales call and lie to a
salesperson and be like uh
oh yeah I want to like test this for
like my local business and like go
through all of that then it's like uh I
I that just makes me feel weird about
like having it having to go through all
that but if it's like you know an
anonymous type of sign up process where
you just like sign up for a trial and uh
what are you doing man he's stepping on
our circuit boards yeah no I I agree
with you Joel I I will say you know I I
have not gone through a sales call and
set up something like that
um but people do and a lot of bug Bounty
is about
how far you're willing to go that other
people won't go So Divine your own
boundaries there I'm not going to tell
you one way or the other what's right or
wrong there
um yeah I won't tell you whether I it's
right or wrong to go to the dark web and
download a pirated version of it you
know like yeah I think whatever you need
to do to get it you know yeah I think
you know there's definitely some some
ethical boundaries there but at the end
of the day
um you know the hacker is going to have
access to that and and and
um you know if you in in your Goodwill
are pursuing security research and
you're not going to try to use this in
it for a negative way then I think each
individual person has to to find their
boundaries with that
um I've got mine set Joel's got his set
and um you know we can we can look at
other people there's been some drama
recently about this so I'll just sort of
monologue about it for just a second uh
you know there's been a lot of people in
this street that have done
things in pursuit of good intent good
faith security research that I would not
do and
um and at the end of the day
I'm not going to say that that's wrong
for them or that that's you know a
problem I just have my my boundaries
where I set my boundaries and I respect
the people that have done differently
and I think that's kind of the way I
would like to see the industry flow
yeah yeah 100 I I feel very very similar
you know set your own boundaries set
your own ethical guidelines but you know
there's always uh the inequal and
opposite reaction to every action right
so just you know be aware that if you uh
cross the boundary too far then that can
always lead to some more negative
consequences uh you know that might not
be intended but uh yeah I mean outside
of free trials
um you can also just like pay for
software right so you can just like you
could buy the product if you really want
to get your hands on it if they don't do
free trials or something all these
things like that we're talking about
these are clear barriers to entries so
generally speaking you can be pretty
well assured that like if this is
something that you're doing majority of
other hackers probably aren't um or
haven't because of that financial burden
or the time burden or the communication
or whatever just their own ethical
boundaries or whatever like the friction
right like that is going to change How
likely somebody else is to go and try
and get that and so if you're willing to
go the extra mile and uh push through it
and work to get that software the harder
than they are then that's going to give
you that Competitive Edge right yeah for
sure and I I um I've recently paid 170
bucks for a code base and uh Mega
dividends my bro like yeah you you see
you see Roi on that all the time
um and 170 bucks like I'm not gonna lie
like I preach on the podcast buy the
product all the time right but like it
was 170 bucks I was like that's still
like you know let me think about this
one for a second I wouldn't spend 170 on
dinner I know really you know like and I
just I heard my own voice in my head
Justin buy the product you know
like Professor Oaks voice
and so I bought it and boom um you know
you get some bugs out of that so
definitely especially I will say on the
lower oh my gosh Laura was hyperactive
this episode yeah no he's he's going
he's going through his tail just like
goes
um yeah so uh definitely definitely
worth worth doing and I will say you
know when the source code is on the on
the cheaper side like 170 Bucks versus
like ten thousand dollars
um you know there's a pretty good chance
that if it's getting sold at that price
point there may have been some
you know edges being cut uh you know in
production so just another lesson that
I've learned along the way that I'll
pass along to you guys uh if it's if
it's cheaper might be easier to hack who
knows yeah for sure
um another thing that we have done in
the past but it is also pretty common is
using like a local file disclosure or an
lfi an lfd any of those for reading
files an arbitrary file read anything
like that to read source code
um this is super useful for stuff like
PHP and any type of like server-side app
that is going to be you know not
basically what you see is not what you
get right so like PHP does a lot of
stuff in the background but you don't
see any of the stuff in the PHP tags or
a python web server is probably doing
some like back-end rendering or
something with that python before it
sends out the response so those are
types of things where it's really really
useful to understand what's going on
from a white box scenario and being able
to see the source code is like a huge a
huge Gateway into like
understanding the application at a
deeper level yeah for sure I I I'm glad
you mentioned python because I didn't
have that on the list here so we just
want to do a list for a couple a couple
things here like if you're if you're
dealing with a job application if you
can pull the um the
jar file down that's easy to to
decompile back down to
um actual readable normal Java using jet
X so that's a good one if you can pull
python python C files you can uncompile
them using uncompile 6.
um if you can pull dot net
binaries you can decompile them using
dot Peak and get access to the full
source code which I did not know until
two live hacking events uh ago and that
was a big game changer once people told
me about that after after the dupe
window ended they're like yeah I was
reading the source code I was like the
source code
how did you do that how did you do that
do you say
um and so very big there and then at the
end of the day worst comes to worse if
it's binary and you can't do anything
else pop out the good old Ida or gidra
and try your look at pulling all the
strings and and that sort of thing you
can to piece together what the code is
doing
yeah 100 these are like probably the
main kind of like core easily decompile
is what I would call them like python
Java
.net yeah specifically
um I think there are probably a couple
others that I'm not thinking of at the
moment but like those are really like if
you have an APK or a jar file you can
get that back to source code very very
easily just the way that Java Works
python same thing the python byte code
generally these languages that have like
an intermediary type of like bytecode
language that it has to use in order to
be like cross-platform compatible yeah
like jvm the python bike Pisces right
like those types of things those make it
easier to decompile them back into the
source code because it's pretty Concrete
in terms of what those instructions are
doing.net is kind of like a weird uh
Edge case here I'm not really sure
why.net is so easy to to like reverse
engineer but yeah dot Peak is an insane
piece of software I've used that for a
number of years it's from jetbrains uh
the people who make idea and pycharm and
all that kind of stuff
um and it's a it's a really really
amazing tool I used it last week for
Something Completely non-bug Bounty
related but uh but yeah no it works uh
every every time I've ever had a net uh
executable that Peak is the way to go
nice yeah that's that's awesome man I I
love that trick and I love adding stuff
like that to my to my repo for um
attacking all these various types of
applications I will I will add a little
disclosure here do not pull source code
via LSD uh if that's not chill and yes
young people like I said other people
will do this but source code is
something that developers are pretty
possessive over uh as you can imagine
because that's their whole thing
um and so uh you know I've definitely
seen some Kickback on these more so than
other pivots
um so definitely get permission from the
team first submit the lfd say hey I
would like to pull source code to try to
affect Integrity rather than just
confidentiality is that chill
um yeah normally yeah that's a great
cutting out yeah that's a great call out
because I think a lot of times you might
be actually going against program scope
if you if you if you go too far and I
think the last thing you want to do is
be writing up your report and and like
as they're reading through it they're
like oh wait to say they like went way
too far with this this is not okay and
it becomes an issue or something that
you have to deal with so it's it you
know the program depends on the program
most programs are pretty chill if you
say hey I have this really awesome bug
I'd like to pursue it further is it okay
if I pull source code or are you okay
with extrapolating the impact from this
point right and yeah and basically leave
it up to them because you could probably
impact like show like way higher
severity if you want but that's going to
be their call whether or not they're
okay with that um source code is
intellectual property so you have to be
aware of that be be careful with that
and and like you said it may just even
be most effective for you as a bug
Bounty Hunter to
just take the bump you know and say like
hey uh don't want to grab source code
you know without your permission yeah
but if I do I'll probably find a bunch
of other bugs and then you know they'll
just say okay yeah sure I'll bump this
to a crit pay out the max Bounty for an
lft I I've sort of ranted about this
before on the Pod I think lfd should
almost always be a crit
um a lot of people put it at highs
because it technically only affects
confidentiality so
um but if it just if it does just affect
confidentiality then I think it's only
fair for them to give you the
opportunity to Pivot and pull source
code and see what you can do
um and if not they need to give you the
bump to crit
yeah yeah 100
um it's just one of those cases where
like you know you hope the program is
understanding and stuff and they're just
like yeah for sure um okay so let's see
the other the other one here that I
wanted to call out
um and we actually see this quite a bit
um between top hackers finding uh Docker
containers for the specific product so
um let's say you don't have access to
the source code for a specific product
you don't have a product key right
um one of the best ways excuse me
for you to get access to the source code
would be to find their Docker container
that they use for Rapid deployment of
the product even if it doesn't have a
key in it right and then pull that
Docker container down uh override the
starting point what is it is it starting
point start point I mean you don't even
have to you can just extract files from
a Docker container yeah with yeah you
can also do that so I I that's generally
what I would do I normally run the
docker container personally and then
jump into it by overriding the
initialization point of the start Point
whatever it's called and just running a
bash interactive shell and then sort of
grapping through the source code but
yeah you know
this is before I learned about the magic
of vs code and so I guess you're going
to want to extract the files out of that
that Docker container copy them into a
directory open it up in vs code and then
do all the things we talked about before
with passcode
but it but it is a really good like
trick basically that you just talked
about there I don't know I don't know if
you realize this but you can make your
own
Docker file basically a patch a Docker
file patch on top of it so if you make a
new Docker file all you have to do is
say at the top from and then your image
name and what it'll do is your image
will then be based off of the other
image and you can just set your own
entry point so you just from Target
image entry point bin Bash that's it
yeah and then you can just start playing
a new solicitation Point entry point
that's what I meant at your point yeah
yeah and I think also um I'm gonna try
to see if I can find it in my in my bash
history right here
um but I think you can also just run it
and then yeah just run exec on it as
well
um yeah you can to bin bash and then
copy stuff out if you want or just use
the docker CP command to pull files out
yep yeah yeah so I I at one point I had
um a set of commands that I use that
will basically it creates a new instance
of an image copies all the files down
into a local folder and then destroys it
oh that's good that's you should put
that in a gist or something and we'll up
upload it after that'd be cool yeah
um okay so the other thing last one that
I wanted to talk well all right I kind
of had two more last one we said the
last yeah
we know we got a couple more interesting
things okay so
um the the other thing is that uh I
don't know why I sort of assumed this in
the past but in the past I've kind of
assumed that if there is a library like
on in PIP for python or npm for node
that that
um library is going to be open source
and on GitHub but that isn't necessarily
the case so there are there are some
times where these um you know packages
are getting pushed to pip into npm and
that sort of thing
um and they are not you can't go find
them and you the source code on GitHub
so some you need to pull those libraries
down and you can read that source code
and sometimes you'll just find like
embedded secrets and reference to
external assets and and like I I've had
people find API keys in there before
that are worth
a lot five five figures um and I think
actually there was a scenario with
Shopify I want to say that was disclosed
not too long ago where uh it was it was
above that I think it was a six-figure
bounty
um yeah so definitely
um keep it in in your mind to audit some
of these public uh source code
um packages and and libraries and look
for not only vulnerabilities there
um but also for Secrets leaking and
stuff like that
yeah 100
um that's like a built-in feature so
like GitHub for example they offer this
thing called package uh GitHub package
registry and you can register you know
custom private packages just for your
org in GitHub right and so
oftentimes a JavaScript library will be
built as a result of webpacking all of
the used libraries into one place and
they'll be like a vendors.js main.js
type of thing and so that's a great way
to like look at an attack scenario
either if they've left
um The Source map files in so you can
see the whole node modules folder and
you can look through their private
modules yeah through the directory
structure or if it's just like in there
and you can like look for keywords like
the company name or something like that
that's like a really great way to get
access to those private libraries that
you're talking about where like it may
have been included accidentally
um we've seen similar type of stuff with
mobile apps where protobuf files for
example yeah protocol files will get you
know used to generate dot Java files
within the app but then that folder of
dot protos gets built into the app as
well like by accident just included as a
build artifact and then oh hey cool now
I have like full you know commented
Proto files which we definitely have not
seen on another Target accidentally uh
seen that lately I think
um no yeah that's Mega helpful and and
yeah I haven't paid as much attention to
vendors.js or whatever stuff before so
I'll definitely make sure I'm I'm not
skipping over that because there could
be some cool stuff in there it's good to
know yeah the last the last thing so
okay so actually this kind of leads into
the report that I was going to talk
about
um so I'll kind of I'll kind of
integrate this yeah let's tie it
together and man we didn't even get to
talk about like okay sources and syncs
and like you know going through the
application and and stuff like that so
man we might we might have to make a
part two to the source code review yeah
um but
the report that I wanted to talk about
today is uh is a report that uh popped
up in a live hacking event three years
ago and essentially what it was was
while we were hacking a specific
application we would get errors you know
when we were fuzzing the API calls or
playing around with the API calls and
those errors would
um return a string that contained the
company's name in it but also contained
like the micro service that we were
talking to the specific name of the
microservice
sorry got my my third's bothering me a
bit today
um and so uh when we we what we would do
is while we were hacking we would take
these strings and we would just boom
throw it in a GitHub search right well
um a couple times in for that uh one of
them popped up and uh that the repo that
had that reference to that microservice
um was a training repo for uh employees
of that company and that training repo
contained a ton of proprietary source
code that was in Live use in their
microservices in production
um and it's so hard you know and it
wasn't even necessarily on the front
level too but the guy had committed his
node modules repo into your his known
modules folder into the GitHub repo and
so like you know one of those modules
you know has a sub module that's also
you know an internal module and then she
just kind to go down and down and down
and uh in until you enumerate all the
source code and um we reported it
directly to company as like now your
production source code is kind of out
there flopping around and they're like
yeah
man
and we're like already then so we we
took uh some of the secrets out of there
and started decrypting stuff uh you know
stuff that they trusted trusted
um data and re-encrypting it and sending
it back we started uh auditing the
source code found like a bunch of
vulnerabilities because of it
um so that's another way to find uh
source code is look at the world's
biggest source code you know provider
GitHub uh just throw it in the GitHub
search and I think it's even better now
when uh now that GitHub has increased
their the effectiveness of their search
so definitely excited to see some cool
finds there
yeah it's super cool I um one of the
things that I I had wanted to mention
earlier in the episode I wrote this down
and
um kind of there was no not a great
place to to drop it but this is this is
like one of those great examples of like
working within like constraints and I
think this is sort of like a gen a more
General like topic that like really
talks about the types of stuff that
makes like hacking like finding really
epic bugs like a lot easier where if
you're making like those types of deep
Dives like it's like too twofold deep
Dives like going as deep as you can like
exploring the source code exploring
whatever like finding like deep
references understanding at almost the
level of an engineer like what is
happening within this application what's
happening across different Services all
that kind of stuff that's like one side
of it the other side of it is figuring
out the constraints setting goals and
then finding ways to get to that goal
within those constraints
um a lot of hacking is like operating
within a constrained environment so
you'll have different permissions or
you'll have a firewall or you'll have a
wife or like whatever that you have to
like work around and all these if
statements and whatever right like the
stuff that you have to like figure out
how to get around and if you can figure
out a creative way to move within those
constraints to get to your end goal
that's where you're going to find like
those really awesome bugs that are that
are like leveraging every little bit of
you know movement and whatever that you
have within this environment to try and
like exploit oh this like weird config
entry or you know this weird like oh
it's in the node modules like within the
vendor.js or whatever right like just
finding like how to you know the program
comes back and says Ah we don't really
care about that okay additional
constraint how do we get around that
like make it so that they do care about
it right yeah so I think just like
finding those constraints is huge yeah
it is and and that's a great way to
framework eyes that whole that whole
process us there and then you know
working around those constraints
requires a very in-depth knowledge of
the product because at the end of the
day those it wasn't you know some those
constraints were put in there by
accident someone's thinking this through
like no this user shouldn't be able to
do this right and so you know it
requires Mastery of the product to to be
able to work within those constraints in
an Artful and beautiful way this is this
is one of the things that really I think
makes hacking an art as well is because
you you do have to
um as much technical documentation and
Technology as it is there's a lot of
creativity that goes around uh you know
working Within These constraints and and
sort of turning the system back on its
head so read the read the bleeping
manual and read the read the manual yeah
and uh definitely you'll be able to find
some some cool stuff like that on the
edge of functionality within the
constraints
yeah super awesome art man I gotta
bounce uh anything else we gotta do
before we end up the Pod I think that's
it dude another great episode awesome
see you man all right catch you later
hey everyone thanks for checking out
this week's episode of the critical
thinking bug Bounty podcast we hope you
liked it for more hacking and Bug
bending content you can find all of our
other episodes wherever you get your
podcasts you can also find our show in a
video format over on YouTube that's
youtube.com criticalthinkingpodcast
please if you wouldn't mind leave us a
rating and share this episode with your
friends and colleagues it helps a ton
and it's the best way to support the
podcast directly next week we've got
another exciting episode coming up so
you're not going to want to miss this
one see you there
[Music]